Ruben E. Reina Papers Mss.Ms.Coll.67 Mss.Ms.Coll.67
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Peten (Box 29-73)
  - Subseries A. Encomiendas y Tierras (Box 29-36)
    - AGCA Expediente 41456, 1657; 2.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 9957, 1658; 4.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 10206, 1658; 26.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 40635, 1662; 16.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 42271, 1662; 4.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 42303, 1663; 4.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 42562, 1663; 3.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 26388, 1664; 6.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 40618, 1665; 4.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 17896, 1668?; 15.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 14146, 1671; 16.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 40467 ?, 1671; 73.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 40655, 1672; 4.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 15207, 1673; 41.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 40561, 1673; 12.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 40503, 1677; 1.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 40532, 1678; 4.0 p (Box 35)
    - A1.3-Legajo 4588, 1683-1699; 264.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 48785, 1688; 3.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 40591, 1691; 12.0 p (Box 35)
    - AGCA Expediente 31436, 1695; 13.0 p (Box 35)
      (Dominicos)
    - AGCA Expediente 4520, 1720; 21.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 52425, 1726; 40.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 39060, 1732; 6.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 57812, 1736; 105.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 11737, 1751; 242.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 53051, 1773; 49.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 11810, 1804; 160.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 37647, 1816; 59.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 10, n.d.; 39.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 10202, n.d.; 5.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 36516, n.d.; 23.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 36517, n.d.; 2.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 40534, n.d.; 1.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 41467, n.d.; 8.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 42329, n.d.; 1.0 p (Box 36)
    - AGCA Expediente 42620, n.d.; 4.0 p (Box 36)
      Nahuatl language
    - AGCA Expediente 42621, n.d.; 12.0 p (Box 36)
    - Notas Medidas de Tierras, n.d.; 12.0 p (Box 36)
  - Subseries B. Libros Antiguos de Cofradias (Box 37-40)
    Series II. Peten. Libros Antiguos de Cofradias
    The Libros Antiguos de Cofradias subseries consists of photocopies of books that are literally translated to "Ancient Books of the Brotherhood," or priests.
    - Animas-Unidentified locations, 1720-1775; Ca. 150 p (Box 37)
      Leg. 1.2
    - Concepcion, 1748-1775; Ca. 100 p. (Box 37)
      Leg. 3.2
    - Cukaha (Totonicpan), 1720-1836; Ca. 70 p (Box 37)
    - Location unknown, 1753-1822
      Leg. 2.2 Unlocated as of 1/2008
    - San Andres Xecul, 1682-1772; Ca. 200 p (Box 37)
      Leg. 4.3
    - San Andres Xecul, 1814-1815; 5.0 p (Box 37)
      Leg. 3.1
    - San Andres Xecul-Baptismos, 1701-1730; Ca. 150 p (Box 37)
      Leg. 3.3
    - San Andres Xecul-Sacramentos, 1762-1809; Ca. 100 p (Box 37)
      Leg. 2.3
    - San Cristobal Totonicapan, 1710-1821; Ca. 200 p (Box 38)
      Leg. 1.4
    - San Cristobal Totonicapan #1, 1750-1839; Ca. 150 p (Box 38)
      Leg. 4.2
    - San Cristobal Totonicapan #2, 1750-1839; Ca. 150 p (Box 38)
    - San Jose de Arriba, 1699-1774; Ca. 100 p (Box 38)
      Leg. 2.1
    - San Jose de Arriba, 1701-1775; Ca. 200 p (Box 38)
    - Santa Cruz, 1776-1836; Ca. 200 p (Box 39)
      Leg. 1.3
    - Senora de la Merced, ciudad de Goathemala, 1539; Ca. 150 p (Box 39)
    - Unidentified location, 1749-1839; Ca. 100 p (Box 39)
      Leg. 2.2
  - Subseries C. Ethnohistorical Data (Box 42-62)
    Photocopies and photographs of documents from local community archives, oral histories, and AGCA. (Portable photocopy and photographic equipment used under poor conditions).
    - Abrir camino, cobro de impuesto, 1870 (Box 42)
    - Arancel: Padilla, 1845 (Box 42)
      Original document
    - Archives Centro America Guatemala--Unclassified Documents, 1692 (Box 42)
    - Asalto a la Guarnicion, 1867 (Box 42)
    - Boundaries with Yucatan, 1863 (Box 42)
    - Breve Renena de un Viaje Desde Balancan, 1927 (Box 42)
    - Cajabon, San Juan de Dios, Sto. Toribio, B. Viejo, San Andres, Chachaclum, La Libertad (varios)—sample, 1889 (Box 42)
    - Carestia de granos, 1911 (Box 42)
    - Catastro, 1922 (Box 42)
    - Cayo--Benque Viejo land use (English), 1909 (Box 42)
    - Censo General del Peten, 1845 (Box 42)
    - Censo Monteria el Caribe, 1880 (Box 42)
    - Chachaclum—(Padron), 1885 (Box 42)
    - Church--Misiones Capuchinas entre los Lacandones Indios, 1864 (Box 42)
    - Church--Priest--Fuga del Padre Bersunza, 1865 (Box 42)
    - Church--Vicario, 1865 (Box 42)
    - Condusion de Vastimentos para Presidio de el Itza, 1699 (Box 42)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #344
    - Correspondencia Corregidor del Peten con Dept. Verapaz, 1869 (Box 42)
    - Criminal, 1871-1893 (Box 42)
    - Croques de Sanidad--Settlement Pattern--Pueblos, 1960 (Box 42)
    - Demography, 2.0 boxes (1 ln. ft.) (Box 49-50)
      - Flores--Age and Sex, 1845 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Age and Sex, 1875 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Censo, 1933 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Censo--Occupations, 1845-1960 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Marriage Analysis, 1950 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Marriage Patterns, 1845-1960 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Mozos for Milpas, 1888 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Occupational Analysis, 1950 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Population Study with Family Names, 1885-1960 (Box 49)
      - Flores--Residents, 1960-1961 (Box 49)
        Includes aerial view of area
      - Flores--Wood (Lumber), 1887 (Box 49)
      - Informant Letters, 1960 (Box 49)
      - Inventario, 1762 (Box 49)
      - Inventario--Schools, 1889 (Box 49)
      - La Libertad--Chachaclun Schools, 1888 (Box 49)
      - Lake Settlements, Informant data, 1960-1961 (Box 49)
      - Languages: San Jose and others (Mopan, Matul, Yucatan), San Luis (Box 49)
      - Livestock, 1888 (Box 49)
      - Maps (Tayasal--Cartografia), n.d. (Box 50)
      - Maps (Tayasal--Region), n.d. (Box 50)
      - Milpas and Milperos, 1964 (Box 50)
      - Milpas and Milperos--Households, Locations, Families (Box 50)
      - Prices, 1888 (Box 50)
      - Pueblos, 1885 (Box 50)
      - San Andres Censo, 1862 (Box 50)
      - San Jose, 1950-1960 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Age and Sex, 1849 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Censo (Copy), 1849 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Censo Study, 1855 (Box 50)
        Demographic patterns, family names
      - San Jose--Censo Study, 1871 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Censo Study, 1875 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Censo Study, 1877 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Censo Study, 1881 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Censo Study, 1885 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Censo Study, 1963 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Censo Transcription, 1878 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Demographic Analysis by Age, Sex, Marriage, 1849-1960 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Economics, 1888 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Human Skulls in Church, 1960 (Box 50)
        Oral histories, letters and manuscripts
      - San Jose--Letters, 1854 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Report, Themes in Peten, 1960 (Box 50)
      - San Jose--Tikal, Macancha, 1885 (Box 50)
      - Santa Ana--Statistics, 1888 (Box 50)
        Articulos, revista mensual de precios, lista de alumnos
    - Denuncias de terrenos, 1894 (Box 42)
    - Documents from AGI, 5.0 box (Box 52-56)
      - Estado 48, 1792; 47.0 p (Box 52)
      - Estado 49, 1798; 131.0 p (Box 52)
      - Estado 49, 1800; 18.0 p (Box 52)
      - Guatemala 151A, 1696; 236.0 p (Box 52)
      - Guatemala 151B, 1698; 17.0 p (Box 52)
      - Guatemala 345, 1698; 162.0 p (Box 52)
      - Guatemala 859, 1765; 103.0 p (Box 52)
      - Indiferente 2979, 1784; 216.0 p (Box 53)
      - Mexico 1040, 237-300, 1722-1724; 64.0 p (Box 53)
      - Mexico 1040, 301-380, 1722-1724; 80.0 p (Box 53)
      - Mexico 1040, 381-440, 1722-1724; 60.0 p (Box 54)
      - Mexico 1040, 441-520, 1722-1724; 80.0 p (Box 54)
      - Mexico 1040, 521-585, 1722-1724; 65.0 p (Box 54)
      - Mexico 3167, 1807; 291.0 p (Box 55)
      - Mexico 3168, 1812-1813; 477.0 p (Box 55)
      - Patronoato 237, 1696; 236.0 p (Box 56)
    - Dolores—(Padron), 1885 (Box 42)
    - Estadistica administrativa, 1915-1916 (Box 42)
    - Expedicion—Progreso via Plancha, 1916 (Box 42)
    - Fabrica aguardiente, centralizacion, 1903 (Box 42)
    - Fajardo (Priest, Informe Peten), 1819 (Box 42)
    - Flores, 1890 (Box 42)
    - Flores--Aguardiente clandestina, 1873 (Box 42)
    - Flores--Census, 1885 (Box 42)
    - Flores--Church administration letter, 1899 (Box 42)
    - Flores--Circular, 1902 (Box 42)
    - Flores--Contratos de Mozos, 1886 (Box 42)
    - Flores--Criminal, 1904 (Box 42)
    - Flores--Cuadro estadistico, pasaportes, siembras comunales, educacion, 1882 (Box 42)
    - Flores--Estadisticas, 1894 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Festejos, 1888 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Gobernador Modesto Mendez, 1846 (Box 43)
    - Flores--History in local journal (publication), 1920 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Juicios, 1896 (Box 43)
    - Flores, La Libertad--Circular, letters, 1911 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Letters to Jefe Politico, 1889 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Letters to Jefe Politico, 1917 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Listas al Servicio de Carminos, 1889 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Mozos--San Jose, 1892 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Mozos--Servicio de caminos, 1883 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Numero de objectos para Exp. Univ., Paris, 1889 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Numeros de Bautismos, Casamientas, 1865 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Ocupaciones, contrabandistas, 1889 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Orden y Tranquilidad, 1871 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Padron, 1862 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Statistics, 1918 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Varios, 1925 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Vecino de San Luis--Derechos pago, 1897 (Box 43)
    - Flores--Venta de propiedad, 1908 (Box 43)
    - Flores y Peten, 1859 (Box 43)
    - Flores y San Jose--Mozos de San Jose para conducir carga a Guatemala, 1891 (Box 43)
    - Greenwald, Ann--Impressions of Life in Peten, 1850s--Manuscript, 1963 (Box 43)
    - Guarnicion de Plaza, 1916 (Box 43)
    - Guatemala--Abusos de Curas regulares Obispado de Goathemala, 1725-1726 (Box 43)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #962
    - Guatemala--Apertura de Caminos, 1549 (Box 43)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #9-97
    - Guatemala--Colegio Santiago, Educacion, 1574 (Box 43)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #165
    - Guatemala--Decreto de Tarifa, 1865 (Box 43)
    - Guatemala--Defraude, Cerrato, 1550 (Box 43)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #968A
    - Guatemala--General, 1546 (Box 43)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #110
    - Guatemala--General, 1687 (Box 43)
    - Guatemala—General, Provincias, 1563 (Box 43)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #9-55
    - Incidente w/ Morley—Killing of Dr. LaFleur during Revolucion, 1916 (Box 43)
    - Indigenos profugos, 1866 (Box 43)
    - Informa Cura Saenz, 1859 (Box 43)
    - Invasiones el Peten, 1866 (Box 43)
    - Inventario Documents in AGCA, 1960 (Box 43)
    - Justicia--Presidio San Jose & el Peten, 1874 (Box 43)
    - La Libertad, 1894 (Box 43)
    - La Libertad, Aldeas, Monterias Padron, 1885 (Box OS)
      San Jose Census. Original document
    - La Libertad--Necesidades, 1880 (Box 43)
    - La Libertad Statistics Report, 1876 (Box 43)
    - Matricular mozos—Corte del palo de tinta, 1880 (Box 44)
    - Mexico--Descripciones de Rios y Costa, Yucatan; Comercios Clandestinos; Costas Campeche; Exp. Palo Tinto, 1751, 1763 (Box 44)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #3099
    - Mexico--Martin de Ursua, 1697 (Box 44)
    - Mexico--Obispo de Yucatan por Servicios Persona de los Indios; Peten Politicamente bajo Yucatan, 1722-1724 (Box 44)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #1020
    - Mexico--Ursua y Defensa del Peten; Abierto Camino al Itza; Sobre Actividades de Gobernador Ursua en Peten, 1701 (Box 44)
      Transcription. AGI Leg. #1014
    - Modesto Mendez visita ruinas arqueologicas de Tikal, 1849 (Box 44)
    - Monteria "Calatrava"--Soc. Torres Sisniega y Cia--Population, 1916 (Box 44)
    - Monteria El Destino (Padron), 1880 (Box 44)
    - Monteria--Empresa The Guatemala and Mexican Mahogany Export Company--Report: population, 1903 (Box 44)
    - Monteria--Nuevo Esperanza, 1902 (Box 44)
    - Monteria--Population, 1902 (Box 44)
    - Monteria San Lorenzo--(Padron), 1885 (Box 44)
    - Monteria Union--(Padron), 1880 (Box 44)
    - Monterias--Lista, 1903 (Box 44)
    - Movimiento de poblacion, 1911 (Box 44)
    - Nomina general American & Guatemalan Mahogany Population, 1916 (Box 44)
    - Notes from Documents, 5.0 box (Box 58-62)
      - Notes from Documents by Cultural Categories after Peter Murdoch, 2.0 boxes (1 ln. ft.) (Box 58-59)
        Classification of the Ethnohistorical Material. Based on Murdock's General Outline (HRAF) Classification #17.
      - Notes from Documents by Events and Cultural Categories, 1.0 box (Box 60)
      - Notes from Documents by Peten Communities, 1.0 box (Box 61)
      - Notes from Documents--Flores, 1600-1929; 1.0 box (Box 62)
    - Padron Monterias "Rebumbio", 1880 (Box 44)
    - Peten--Archivo Centro America, Archivo Flores, Unclassified copies, 1781-1860 (Box 44)
      Transcriptions
    - Peten--Documentos Oficial, 1869 (Box 44)
    - Peten--Estadistico de Artesanos, 1866 (Box 44)
    - Peten Ethnohistorical Notes, 1695-1771; 184.0 p (Box 44)
      Notes by Reina from Documents 1695-1771 at AGI. Visited during the Summer 1964, pre-Hispanic-American Project.
    - Peten Ethnohistorical Notes, 1700-1960; 141.0 p (Box 44)
      Notes by Reina on Peten, 1700-1960. Source: Local Peten archives. Visited 1960-1961.
    - Peten--Extraccion de hule y chicle, 1904 (Box 44)
    - Peten--Extratos, 1899 (Box 44)
    - Peten--Informes de pueblos, 1894 (Box 44)
    - Peten--Instrucciones para Padron de pueblos i aldeas, 1902
      NOT FOUND
    - Peten--Justicia, 1897 (Box 44)
    - Peten--Ninos vacunados, 1861 (Box 44)
    - Peten--Nombre de plantas medicinales, 1913 (Box 44)
    - Peten--Nombre de reos, 1909 (Box 45)
    - Peten pueblos—Estado Sanitario, 1895 (Box 45)
    - Peten--Registro de Mexicanos residentes--Lista de pasajeros por Plancha de Piedra, 1916 (Box 45)
    - Peten--Rentas municipales, 1893 (Box 45)
    - Peten--Servicio de caminos por pueblos, 1889 (Box 45)
    - Peten--Union Centroamericana--Politica, actas, 1890 (Box 45)
    - Peten--Varios, 1912 (Box 45)
    - Peten, varios--Consumo de harina, estadistica, 1911 (Box 45)
    - Pinelo & Alvarado--Possibility of building a railroad, 1919 (Box 45)
    - Plancha de Piedra--Aduana, 1889 (Box 45)
    - Population--Summary by Pueblos, 1886 (Box 45)
    - Presidio Peten Itza, 1750 (Box 45)
    - Publications (Box 51)
      - Administration of the Indies Articles, various dates; 9.0 Item(s) (Box 51)
        Photocopies
      - Anales de la sociedad de geografia y historias, various dates; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 51)
      - FYDEP Publications, n.d. (Box 51)
      - Informe Sobre el departmento del Peten, dirijido al Ministerio de Fomento, 1951 (Box 51)
      - List of Events, 1785-1864 (Box 51)
      - Local Publications (Box 51)
      - Maya Trade Routes (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 51)
      - Modesto Mendez (Box 51)
      - Sixteenth and Seventeenth Century Reports on the Chol Maya, Thompson, J. Eric S., (John Eric Sidney), 1898-1975 (Box 51)
      - Socotz, Belize, Thompson, J. Eric S., (John Eric Sidney), 1898-1975 (Box 51)
    - Pueblo San Benito Censo, 1885 (Box 45)
    - Pueblos--Cultivo Algodon (cotton), 1864 (Box 45)
    - Pueblos Nuevos, 1862 (Box 45)
    - Reduccion de Indios Ahitza, Peten, 1699 (Box 45)
    - Reduccion de los Indios Ahitza--Ejecuto el Gral. Don Martin de Ursua y Arismendi (Transcription), 1700 (Box 45)
      AGI Leg. #343 N.21
    - Refugiados--Colonia Belize, 1880 (Box 45)
    - Relacion Sobre Reduccion de Indios, 1704 (Box 45)
    - Respuestas de Antonio Villar a las Acusaciones de Fajardo, 1819 (Box 45)
    - Resumen--Poblacion, economia, milicia--Estadistica, 1909 (Box 45)
    - Revolucion, 1916 (Box 45)
    - Revolucion contra Jefe Politico Matus, 1872 (Box 45)
    - San Andres, Aldea San Juan, 1890 (Box 46)
    - San Andres--Mozos para el transporte de polvora, 1882 (Box 46)
    - San Andres--(Padron), 1885 (Box 46)
    - San Andres y San Jose Visit, 1792 (Box 46)
    - San Benito--Letter, 1890 (Box 46)
    - San Benito--Letter, 1894 (Box 46)
    - San Jose, 1850 (Box 46)
      Census
    - San Jose, 1851 (Box 46)
    - San Jose, 1853 (Box 46)
    - San Jose, 1856 (Box 46)
    - San Jose, 1864 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Acta de bautismo, 1859 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Acta de Nacimiento, 1857 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Acta Municipal, 1876 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Acta Municipal, 1877 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Actas de bautismo, Actas municipal, 1862 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Actas de Gobernador Ambrocio Tut, 1850 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Actas municipales, 1861 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Administracion, 1921 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Aldea Tikal (Padron), 1878 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Ambrocio Tut, 1848 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Armas--Totoposte, 1892 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Bautismos, Church Records, 1863 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Cargas, La Libertad, 1881 (Box 46)
      Carta al juez
    - San Jose--Cartas--Transporte de zinc, 1896 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Census, 1855 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Census, 1856 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Circular, 1924 (Box 46)
    - San Jose Data, 1764-1790 (Box 46)
    - San Jose Data, 1806 (Box 46)
    - San Jose Data, 1816-1818
    - San Jose Data, 1825-1826 (Box 46)
    - San Jose Data, 1831 (Box 46)
    - San Jose Data, 1838 (Box 46)
    - San Jose Data, 1839 (Box 46)
    - San Jose Data, 1841-1846 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Declaracion de escopeta, 1897 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Delitos en Guatemala, 1925 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Diezmos y primicias, 1867 (Box 46)
    - San Jose Educacion, 1878 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--1890--Elecciones (Incomplete) (Box 46)
    - San Jose (Flores)--Lista al servicio personal; Mozos para oficiales en Flores, 1889 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Fondos municipales, 1882 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Informe Sefactura Politica, 1925 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Internal Life, 1855 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Letter, 1887 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Letters y Circulares, 1924-1925 (Box 46)
    - San Jose--Matrimonios, 1894 (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Matrimonios, 1895 (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Municipalidad, decretos, 1881 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron), 1871 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron), 1872 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron), 1873 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron), 1875 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron), 1876 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron), 1877 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron), 1878 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron), 1881 (Box 47)
    - San Jose (Padron)--1882--(Includes Aldea Macanche) (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Pidiendo inspeccion official, 1879 (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Request Marriage, 1882 (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Salario para oficiales, 1888
    - San Jose; San Andres--Registro civil--Matrimonios, 1893 (Box 47)
    - San Jose, S. Benito, San Andres--Sobre escuelas, problemas, 1914 (Box 47)
      (Typed copy) Revolution of 1916
    - San Jose--Sentencias locales--Acusaciones--Acta, 1857-1858 (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Sobre propiedad--Visitas jefe politico, 1901 (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Social Problems, 1885 (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Testamentos--Wills, 1860 (Box 47)
    - San Jose--Visit, report, 1920 (Box 47)
    - San Luis--(Padron), 1885 (Box 47)
    - Santa Ana--Acta Municipal, 1886 (Box 47)
    - Santa Ana--(Padron), 1885 (Box 47)
    - Santa Ana--Sobre Limites, 1890 (Box 47)
    - Santa Barbara--(Padron), 1885 (Box 47)
    - Santo Toribio--(Padron), 1885 (Box 47)
    - Shufeldt v. Republic of Guatemala (Chicle case), 1929 (Box 47)
      Department of State, Arbitration Series No. 3.
    - Sobre administracion publica--Pueblos, salubridad, etc., 1868 (Box 48)
    - Sobre identidad de Peteneros, 1873 (Box 48)
    - Sobre pueblos de Montana--Laguna Santa Cruz, Laguna Santa Clara, 1867 (Box 48)
    - Sobre Reduccion de Ahitza (Transcription), 1700 (Box 48)
      AGI Leg. #343
    - Sobre siembra de platano en luna llena, 1867 (Box 48)
    - Solicitud: permiso para acto religioso, procesiones, 1911 (Box 48)
    - Termino de Guerra Casta en Yucatan, 1849 (Box 48)
    - Transcriptions, 1533-1899; 1.0 box (Box 57)
      Sources: Local archives, oral histories, AGCA
    - Varios--Estadistica, administracion, 1914 (Box 48)
    - Vicario Domingo Fajardo Juez Eclesiastico Provincia Peten--Report on social conditions, 1819; 2.0 folders (Box 48)
      Transcription
    - Visits to Pueblos, 1865 (Box 48)
    - Vital statistics--Dolores, Flores, Las Sabanas, 1870 (Box 48)
    - Volante--Patria y justicia, 1915 (Box 48)
    - Yucatan. Peten (Vulgo--Latin)--Unclassified Doc.--Guatemala, 1863 (Box 48)
  - Subseries D. Peten Court Records (Box 63-71)
    Scope and Contents
    The Peten Court Records consist of photocopies of documents from the Archivo General de Centroamerica in Guatemala. The records are arranged by offense. These copies have acquired particular significance as the original documents were destroyed by a city flood in the 1980s.
    - Index from Archives (Box 63)
    - Aborto, 1864, 1894 (Box 63)
    - Abusos de autoridad, 1859-1891 (Box 63)
    - Abusos de autoridad--Flores, 1860-1898 (Box 63)
    - Agresion, 1861-1898 (Box 63)
    - Agresion--Resistencia, 1871-1882 (Box 63)
    - Allanamiento, 1882-1892 (Box 63)
    - Calumnia, 1837-1895 (Box 63)
    - Calumnia, 1893 (Box 63)
    - Clandestinista--Varios delitos, 1878-1881 (Box 63)
    - Clandestinistas, 1863-1874 (Box 63)
    - Contrabando, 1860-1897 (Box 63)
    - Contrabando--Flores, San Andres, San Jose, 1866-1896 (Box 63)
    - Danos--San Andres, Flores, 1892-1894 (Box 64)
    - Defraudacion--San Andres, Flores, 1883-1896 (Box 64)
    - Defraudacion--Various, 1883-1899 (Box 64)
    - Delitos de varias ramas, 1858-1897 (Box 64)
    - Demanda--Flores, 1886-1897 (Box 64)
    - Desacato a la autoridad, 1845-1885 (Box 64)
    - Desacato--San Andres, Flores, 1826-1899 (Box 64)
    - Estafa, 1882-1883 (Box 64)
    - Estafas--Flores, 1869-1895 (Box 64)
    - Falsificacion de documentos, 1884-1885 (Box 64)
    - Fuga, 1862-1889 (Box 64)
    - Homicidios, 1832-1886 (Box 65)
    - Homicidios San Andres, 1829-1890 (Box 65)
    - Homicidios--Flores, 1834-1899 (Box 65)
    - Hurto, 1874 (Box 65)
    - Hurtos--Flores, 1834-1899 (Box 65)
    - Hurtos--San Andres, 1844-1896 (Box 65)
    - Incendios, 1823-1897 (Box 66)
    - Incendios, 1873-1892 (Box 66)
    - Injurias, 1826-1898 (Box 66)
    - Injurias, 1845-1898 (Box 67)
    - Injurias, 1875-1898 (Box 67)
    - Malversacion de fondos, 1879-1893 (Box 68)
    - Muertes, 1832-1897 (Box 68)
    - Muertes--Flores, 1899 (Box 68)
    - Muertes--San Andres, 1890, 1899 (Box 68)
    - Ofensas sexuales, 1860-1898 (Box 69)
    - Ofensas Sexuales--Flores, 1868-1869 (Box 69)
    - Ofensas Sexuales--San Andres, 1822-1889 (Box 69)
    - Perjurias, 1874-1879 (Box 70)
    - Rina, 1852-1880 (Box 70)
    - Rina--Flores, 1854-1863 (Box 70)
    - Robo--Hurtos, 1844-1899 (Box 70)
    - San Jose--Crimes, 1852-1897 (Box 71)
    - Sedicion, 1853-1880 (Box 71)
    - Servicio, 1854-1863 (Box 71)
    - Varias ramas, 1856-1899 (Box 71)
  - Subseries E. Transcriptions (Box 72-73)
    Transcriptions 5 x 8 cards - transcriptions of the Peten Court Records from the Archivo General de Centroamerica in Guatemala. The cards were prepared by student assistants throughout several years. Not all documents have been verified for accuracy. Each card has the identification number of the document at the upper left.
    - Contrabando -- Communities -- 1860-1897 (Box 72)
    - Contrabando -- Flores -- 1866-1896 (Box 72)
    - Defraudacion -- Communities -- 1882-1896 (Box 72)
    - Defraudacion -- Flores, San Andres -- 1883-1896 (Box 72)
    - Desacatos -- Flores -- 1826-1894 (Box 72)